Literatura de Cordel collection, 1918-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Love Stories., 1918-1995.
  - Title: O homem que nasceu pra ser chifrudo e as 3 mulheres galheiras Author: "O Carioca" Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1940. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: A história do encontro de João Solteiro e Maristela Casada Author: Ségrio M. Pereira Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic SERGIO., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: A confissão de um paquerador, não há dinheiro que pague Author: Nabo Seco Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: Uma peinha de nada no sistema de quadrão Author: José de Souza Campos Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: As quatro órfãs de Portugal ou o valor de honestidade Author: João Melquiades da Silva de Souza Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: A sorte do preguiçoso Author: Manoel D'almeida Filho Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco Other: acrostic, ALMEIDA., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: História de Ubirajara e o Indio Pojucan Author: Severino Milanês da Silva Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 20/07/76. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: História do papagaio misterioso, Os sofrimentos do Jobão Author: Luis da Costa Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 21/5/54. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: História do papagaio misterioso, O jardineiro raptou a princesa dentro do saco Author: Luis da Costa Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: A vingança do filho do seringueiro Author: Manoel Monteiro Publisher: A "Estrella" da Poesia., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: O Valente Sebastião Author: Manoel Camilo dos Santos Publisher: A "Estrella" da Poesia., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: Consultório Sentimental do Dr. Anacas Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Publisher: R. S. Helena., 1981. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title: A cama que matou a noiva no gozo da lua de merda Author: K. Gay Nawara Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., junho de 1983. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O casamento do rapaz macho e fêmia com a moça fêmia e macho Author: H. Romeu Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic H.ROMEU., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O casamento do rapaz macho e fêmia com a moça fêmia e macho Author: José Hermínio do Nascimento Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: Ronaldo e Susana no Rio do Miramar Author: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Publisher: M. C. e Silva., 27/06/75. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: A filha do pescador Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 29/2/52. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: A fada do bosque negro e a Princesa Safira Author: Antonio Américo de Medeiros Publisher: Tip. Pontes Other: acrostic, ANTONIO AMERICO., 23/02/1981. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: Entre o amor e a morte Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 22/02/1980. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O romance da princesa do reino do mar-sem-fim Author: unknown Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic BORGES., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: Historia de Roques Mateus no Rio de São Francisco Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O balão do destino ou a menina da ilha Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda. Other: acrostic ATAIDE., 12/12/1977. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O filho do heroi João de Calais Author: Adalgiso Carlos de Oliveira Publisher: João Severo Other: acrostic ACARLOS., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: Carinhos da madrugada Author: Pedro Salvador Publisher: Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte., 1981. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: A duqueza de Sodoma Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: acrostic, DELARME., 27/8/54. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: A duqueza de Sodoma Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: acrostic, DELARME., 30/10/74. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: A duqueza de Sodoma Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Lira Nordestina Other: acrostic, DELARME., 30/11/80. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: As proezas de Antonio Bacana na fazenda do Tomaz Author: Antonio Bacana Tomaz Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: O principe Edimundo contra o feiticeiro da montanha Author: João Vicente Emiliano Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title: As quatro [sic] de Portugal, ou da honestidade Author: João Melquiades da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Spine of pamphlet is hand sewn.
  - Title: O romance de um sentenciado Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: ATAIDE., 7/30/50. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Romance de Iracema a virgem dos lábios de mel Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 29/04/1978. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: As bravuras de uma mulher sertaneja Author: Francisco de Souza Campos Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, F.SALES., 07/09/77. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Rear wrapper advertises "Ind. Gráfica Verdes Mares" in Recife, PE.
  - Title: Rosa Branca ou a filha do pescador Author: Luis da Costa Pinheiro Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 08/09/80. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: O rapaz que casou com uma porca em Alagoas Author: José Soares Illustrator: signed J.B. Publisher: Folhetaria Borges., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: O boiadeiro valente Author: S. Carlos Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, SCARLOS., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: O rapaz que mamou dois anos nos peitos da namorada Author: José Carlos Illustrator: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila signed DILA Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, JOSECARLOS., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Branca de Neve e os 7 anões Author: Severino Borges Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, BORGES., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Historia de D. Genevra Author: José Bernardo Silva Publisher: J.B. da Silva., 24 de setembro de 1936. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Grande debate do terror do norte com João Miguel, em defeza de Marilene Author: José Bernardo Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Tip. São Francisco., 29/7/55. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Gregorio e Rosalinda ou o ladrão misterioso Author: José Martins dos Santos Illustrator: signed ETS Publisher: Universidade Federal de Alagoas Place: Maceió., 1976. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: O grande romance o reino da esperança Author: Cipriano Barauna Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Manoel Camilo dos Santos Place: Guarabira, Paraíba Other: acrostic CIPRIANO BARAUNA., 25 de setembro de 1962. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Romance do pavão mysterioso historia completa Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: O romance da Princeza Walquira ou O reino da tirania Author: João Severo da Silva Publisher: J.S. da Silva Other: acrostic, J.S.CICERO., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Rear wrapper contains a poem that advertises Relojoaria São Francisco in João Pessoa.
  - Title: Historia de Lindaliz de Monte Carlos Author: Arinos de Belem Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 14/2/50. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Romance do Principe Guidon e o cisne branco Author: Severino Milanez da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Raquel e a fera encantada Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 2/08/1980. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Romance do escravo grego Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda. Other: ATAIDE., 28/07/77. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title: Julita e Galindo Author: Manoel Apolinario Pereira Publisher: João José da Silva Place: Recife Other: acrostic, APOLINARIO., 01/12/77. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O garimpeiro ou Elias e Lucia Author: José Bernardo da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Moça beija no escuro pra poder casar ligeiro, Os cães sempre dão latidos quando a caravana passa Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Debate de Lampião com S. Pedro, acompanha ABC do amor Author: José Pacheco Illustrator: signed Walderêdo Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 29/6/75. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O defensor da honra, ou João Miguel e Marilene Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 28/2/1977. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O defensor da honra, ou João Miguel e Marilene Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 30/6/80. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O dicionario do amor Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O dicionario do amor Author: José Costa Leite Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, COSTALEITE., ca. 1974. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Historia de Romeu e Julieta Author: José Bernardo da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 21/1/57. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Côco Verde e Melancia ou Armando e Rosa Author: José Camelo de Melo Resende Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada Other: acrostic, JOSECAMELO., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: A coragem de Juquinha pelo amor de Ivonete Author: Pedro Armando dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Other: acrostic, ARMANDO., 1977. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: ABC dos namorados, do amor, do beijo, da dança Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada., 1959. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: As bravuras de Ismael em defesa do amor Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A. A. dos Santos Other: acrostic, AALVES., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O balão do destino ou A menina da ilha Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 10/12/1977. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Como triunfa o amor Author: Pedro Armando dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Chiquinho e Juliana o amor que vence Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Note on rear wrapper reads: "A literatura de cordel é o carro alegórico que ajuda o mobral, é escada de luz. Não seja um analfabeto."
  - Title: Dimas e Madalena nos labirintos da sorte Author: Manoel Pereira Sobrinho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada Other: acrostic, PEREIRA., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: O amor em face do destino Author: Manoel D'Almeida Filho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Other: acrostic, ALMEIDA., after 1950. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Cidrão e Helena, acompanha O romance de João Besta e a jia da lagoa Author: Severino Gonçalves de Oliveira, Francisco Sales de Arêda Illustrator: signed MARIRNO 78 Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Other: acrostic, CIRILO, FSALES., ca. 1978. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: Amor e Martírio de uma escrava Author: João Firmino Cabral Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada Other: acrostic, FIRMINO., 1977. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Title: História de Juvenal e o dragão Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: signed STÊNIO Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que cazou com a jumenta Author: Olegario Fernandes da Silva Illustrator: signed JBORGES Publisher: Folheteria Boa Vista., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que deixou a mulher para viver com uma jumenta na Paraíba Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista., ca. 1976. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que deixou a mulher para viver com uma jumenta na Paraíba Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Other: 2a edição., ca. 1976. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que deixou a mulher para viver com uma jumenta na Paraíba Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Other: 6a edição., 26/03/79. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Estória de Braz e Anália Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1980. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: História do principe João Corajoso e a princesa do Reino Não Vai Ninguem Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1980. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Os heróis do amor Magomante e Lindalva Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 7/6/65. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O horóscopo sexual das mulheres Author: Seu Mané do Talo Dentro Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Història de Rosa e Maximiano Author: Severino Milanês da Silva Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 15/01/82. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Historia do poéta Ramos Patrício e Zulmira Feitosa Author: José Camelo [...] Publisher: Sebastião Jesé do Nascimento Other: acrostic, JOSÉCAMELO., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: História de Rosa Branca, ou a filha do pescador Author: José Bernardo da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 13/8/49. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem gosta de mulher e mulher gosta de dinheiro Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: História de Rosa de Milão Author: Teodoro Ferraz da Câmara Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 08/08/77. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: As lutas de Jurandir e o amor de Lucimar Author: João Firmino Cabral Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Folhetaria Borges Other: acrostic, FIRMINO., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O principe Oscar e a rainha das aguas Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: acrostic, JBERNARDO DA SILVA., 25/4/58. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Lindalva e o indio Juracy Author: José Cordeiro Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1979. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O lôbo do oceano Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: 2o volume; acrostic, ATAIDE., 9/6/50. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O principe Roldão e a princesa Lídia Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: O principe Zorobabel e a princesa Ivonete Author: José Costa Leite Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Cinco anos de prisão Author: Cícero Vieira da Silva Publisher: Tip. da Folhetaria Pontes Other: acrostic, CICERO VIEIRA., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Marina e Valdemar Author: José Amaro Pereira Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1979. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Tarciana e Juarêz Author: João de Barros Illustrator: signed J.B. Publisher: J. Barros Other: acrostic, JOAOBARROS., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Vicente e Josina Author: José Pacheco Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Title: Os sofrimentos de Ana e as bravuras de Manoel Pinheiro na fazenda flor do bosque Author: Luis Galdino de Araujo Publisher: L. G. de Araujo., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Manassés e Marilí entre a luta e o amor Author: Manoel Cândido da Silva Publisher: João José da Silva., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Mílton e Cléa, Segue o namoro moderno Author: Luiz da Costa Pinheiro Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 28/11/1976. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: O monstro da serra negra, ou Noberto e Madalena Author: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Publisher: M. C. e Silva., 1978. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Mariana e o capitão do navio Author: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Illustrator: signed STÊNIO Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 30/10/80. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: A maneira da mulher não ter filhos Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Other: 3a edição., outubro 1973. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: O lôbo do amazonas ou Lindomar e Jacira Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 14/2/74. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: A morte de Alonso e a vingança de Marina Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Casa Athayde., 11/6/1942. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Os martírios de Emília e as crueldades de Adolfo Rico Author: Joaquim Batista de Sena Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1975. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Sandoval e Helena ou fera do Paraná Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 1976. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Os sofrimentos de Selma ou fruto da traição Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., 26 de fevereiro de 1979. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: O segredo de Verônica Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 8/11/1978. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Os martirios de Jorge e Carolina Author: João Martins da Athayde Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 31/03/82. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: João Noberto e Luciana Author: João de Cristo Rei Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Josimar e Anita ou o Galo de Ouro Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, J.COSTA., 1974. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Julita e Galdino Author: Manoel Apolinário Pereira Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, APOLINARIO., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Josué e Geraldina Author: Incógnita Illustrator signed ABS Publisher: Heleno Guilherme., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Laureano e Carminha Author: Goriatan? Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, GORIATAN., 01/11/77. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Advertisement for "Ind. Gráfica Verdes Mares" in Recife on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Romance de Roldão e Teresinha Author: Joaquim Luis Sobrinho Publisher: João José da Silva., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Lourival e Givanete Author: Inacio Francisco da Silva Illustrator: signed NACIO Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Title: Romance de João Cambadinho e a princesa do Reino de Mira-Mar Author: Inàcio Carioca Illustrator: José Costa Leite signed JCL Publisher: unknown., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O rapaz que beijou o pai da moça, enganado Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic COSTALEITE., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Romance do pavão misterioso Author: João Melquiades Ferreira Illustrator: signed STENIO Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 30/09/1980. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Rosa Branca ou A filha do pescador Author: Luiz da Costa Pinheiro Illustrator: signed STENIO Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 08/19/80. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O rapaz que casou com uma porca no estado de Alagôas Author: José Soares Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Folhetaria Borges., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O rapaz que apanhou das moças por não saber namorar Author: Caetano Cosme da Silva Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Folhetaria Borges Other: acrostic, CAETANO., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O menino das bodinhos e a princesa interesseira Author: Joaquim Luis Sobrinho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, JOAQUIM., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Uma mulher traiçoeira Author: José Pedro Pontual Publisher: Edson Pinto da Silva Other: acrostic, PONTUAL., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O malandro e a pinqueira no chumbrêgo da orgia Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, PONTUAL., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O malandro e a pinqueira no chumbrêgo da orgia Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, PONTUAL., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O malandro e a pinqueira no chumbrêgo da orgia Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: signed JCL Editor: José Nilton de Oliveira Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina Other: acrostic, PONTUAL., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O macaco misterioso Author: João José da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: J. J. da Silva Other: acrostic, JOSILVA., after 1947. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O mistério dos três anéis Author: João Martins de Athayde (cover), Delarme Monteiro Silva (inside cover) Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: acrostic, DELARME., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Mabel, ou lágrimas de mãe Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Lira Nordestina Other: acrostic, DELARME., ca. 1980. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: A mulher que virou homem no sertão da Paraíba e casou-se Author: João Severo da Silva, "Cícero" Publisher: Folhetaria São João Other: acrostic, J.SEVERO., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Os martírios de Rosa de Milão Author: Teodoro Ferraz da Câmara Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 8/10/1981. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: João Peitudo, o filho de Lampião e Maria Bonita Author: Abraão Batista Publisher: Lira Nordestina., after 1950. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Advertisement for "Café Itaytera" on rear wrapper.
  - Title: João Sabido e o cacetinho mágico Author: Vicente Vitorino de Melo Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1960. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Marcelo, o filho da governanta Author: Delarme Monteiro Filho Illustrator: signed J.BARROS Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco., 12/7/74. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: A louca da sepultura Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Lira Nordestina Other: acrostic ESSILVA., 20/04/1980. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Lágrimas de amor ou a vingança de um condenado Author: Caetano Cosme da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic CAETANO., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: História de João Pinheiro e Mirian Author: Manoel Luis Pereira Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: M. L. Pereira., after 1940. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: O homem que deixou a mulher para viver com uma jumenta Author: Antonio Patricio Illustrator: signed LUCENA 1982 Publisher: Grafica Vitória Ltda.. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Title: Amor de mãe Author: José Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda., after 1960. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Title: O principe e a fada Author: unknown Editor: José Bernardo da Silva Publisher: Tip. São Francisco., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Title: Romance do principe que veio ao mundo sem ter nascido Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro., 20/2/63. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Title: Romance do principe que veio ao mundo sem ter nascido Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Other: ATAIDE Place: Juazeiro., 14/11/53. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Title: Història do poeta Ramos Patrício e Zulmira Feitosa Author: [Jose Camelo] Publisher: Sebastião José do Nascimento Other: acrostic, JOSECAMELO., 1900s. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Item missing front and rear wrappers.
  - Title: História da Donzela Teodora Author: Leandro Gomes de Barros (cover), João Martins de Athayde (inside cover) Publisher: Lira Nordestina., 10/03/82. (Box 9, Folder 4)